Kabuto, I'll tell you
about this kid later...
(大蛇丸)カブト… この子のことは
あとで説明してあげるわ。
More importantly...
それより 後ろの子ネズミ３匹も
ここへ呼んだら どう？
Why don't you call over
the three little mice behind you?
《ヤマト : すべて
お見通しってわけか》
So he's seen through
everything, huh...?
《サクラ : 合図！》
There's the signal!
(カブト)また キミか。
You again, huh...?
(大蛇丸)フフ… いく度か 見た顔ね。
I've seen that face often...
九尾の子もいるみたいだし…
少し 遊んであげましょうかね。
And it looks like
the Nine-Tails kid is here, too...
Maybe I'll play with
you guys a little.
(大蛇丸)サスケ君と どっちが
強くなってるか 見てあげるわ。
Let's see who's become stronger...
you or Sasuke.
Give Sasuke...
(ナルト)サスケを… 返せ!!
back...!
返せは ないだろう？ ナルト君。
"Give him back" is not the correct
way of saying it, Naruto...
ずれてるよ それ。
Your reasoning is off...
(カブト)サスケ君は 望んで
我々のもとに来たんだ。
Sasuke came to us
because he wanted to.
For a man, you're too obsessed...
about the past.
引きずりすぎだよ 男のくせに。
未練たらしいね。
You need to resign yourself.
(サクラ)黙れ メガネ!!
Shut up, four-eyes!
You don't even know
how Naruto feels...
そうやって 冷静になんでも…。
ナルトの気持も知らないくせに！
Stop acting so cold
about everything!
サスケ君のことが知りたいなら➡
If you want to know about Sasuke,
力ずくで 私から
聞き出してみなさい。
try forcing it out of me...
できればだけど。
If you can, that is...
うおぉ～っ!!
The Nine-Tails Unleashed
《ナルト！ これって…》
Naruto...
What is this?!
《サイ : なんだ？ あれは…》
What is that?
I see...
((自来也 : そうか…。
やはり 出てきたか。
So it appeared just as I thought...
(カカシ)おそらく
あのチャクラの形状からして➡
Judging from the shape
of the Chakra,
尾は どんどん増えていき
最終的には ９本になる。
the number of tails will probably
continue to grow...and eventually...
there will be nine.
そういうことだのう…。
That's about the size of it...
(カカシ)自来也様は
いったい 何本目まで？
Master Jiraiya, how many tails
have you seen?
わしは 今までに
二度 死にかけたことがある。
I've come close...
to dying twice...
The first time, I broke
six ribs and both arms,
(自来也)一度目は
アバラ６本と両の腕が骨折➡
and several of my
internal organs ruptured...
内臓破裂が数か所。
(自来也)温泉で
女風呂を覗こうとして➡
It was when I tried to peek into
the women's bath at a hot spring
綱手 お前に
思いっきりやられたときだ。
and you pounded me good, Tsunade...
そして もう一度が…。
The other time was...
ナルトとの修業中➡
during Naruto's training
アイツの九尾チャクラの
４本目の尾を見たときだ。
when I saw the fourth tail
of the Nine-Tails Chakra.
怒りが引き金となり➡
His anger became the trigger
妖狐の尾が生え 増えていった。
and the number of Fox Spirit tails
he grew increased.
(自来也)その妖狐の尾が
３本目のときまでは➡
He maintained consciousness up
until the third Fox Spirit tail.
アイツも 意識を保っていたが…。
４本目で
ついに見境がなくなり➡
But by the fourth tail,
he had lost all rationality and was
controlled by destructive impulses.
破壊衝動に支配されていった。
(自来也)まるで
小さな九尾の妖狐だ。
He was just like a small version
of the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit.
四代目の封印式があるのに➡
Even with the
Fourth Hokage's seal
そこまで…。
うむ。
it can go that far?
Yes.
詳しくは わからぬが
はっきり言えることは➡
I don't know the details,
but I can say this for certain:
四代目の封印術が
弱まりつつあるのではないか➡
The Fourth Hokage's Sealing Jutsu
might very well...
ということだのう。
be weakening.
(綱手)あの四代目の封印術が…。
The Fourth Hokage's Sealing Jutsu...?
そんなことが…。
I can't believe it...
(自来也)それとだ。
There's more...
ナルトは 九尾状態において➡
It may appear that when Naruto
is in the Nine-Tails state,
he's being protected by
the Nine-Tail's Cloak...
チャクラが かたどる 妖狐の衣に
守られているように見えるが➡
実際には
逆に 妖狐の衣によって➡
But in actuality, his body was
continuing to suffer damage
from the Nine Tail's Cloak itself.
体にダメージを受け続けていた。
４本目の尾が出たとき➡
After the fourth tail formed,
妖狐の衣をまとったヤツの体は
血まみれ➡
his body, wrapped in the Nine-Tail's
Cloak, grew bloodied,
and he thrashed about
despite suffering serious injuries.
重傷を負いながら 暴れていた。
妖狐の衣が消えたとき➡
After the Nine-Tail's Cloak
dissipated,
ナルトの傷ついた体は➡
his wounded body
体内の九尾チャクラで回復する。
was healed by the Nine-Tails Chakra
inside his body.
But if he continues to get hurt
…が あんなスピードで負傷と超回復を
繰り返していたら➡
and then heal at that
speed over and over...
Naruto's body will break down
and his life span will shorten.
確実に ナルトの体は蝕まれ
寿命を縮めてしまう。
That's why we need you...
Yamato!
だからこそ お前が必要なのだ
ヤマト。
(綱手)初代火影様の細胞を
受け継いだ お前がな。
You, who has inherited the cells
of the First Hokage.
(自来也)今や 人柱力を
コントロールできる可能性があるのは➡
Now you're the only one...
who can control
the Jinchuriki Host.
お前だけだ。
(自来也)幸いなことに
初代の首飾りは➡
Fortunately for us,
Naruto happens to be wearing
the First Hokage's necklace...
ちょうど
ナルトが かけとるからのう。
(自来也)頼んだぞ))
We're counting on you...
ナルト君 人柱力として
かなり成長してるね。
Naruto... you've grown considerably
as a Jinchuriki Host.
《カブト : 九尾の力が
どんどん強くなってるな》
The power of the Nine-Tails
is rapidly getting stronger...
The striking feature of
the "Jinchuriki Host" is
((チヨ婆 : 人柱力は 尾獣と共鳴し➡
how it utilizes unbelievable power
by resonating with the "Tailed Beast."
(信じられぬ力を使えるのが
特徴じゃ…))
《ナルト！》
Naruto...
フッ…。
人柱力らしく
なっちゃってるわね。
You're starting to become more like
a Jinchuriki Host, aren't you...
ナルト君。
Naruto?
《なるほどね…》
I get it...
それで キミが…
見張り役に 選ばれたのね。
So that's why you were chosen to
keep watch over him, huh?
私の実験も
少しは 役に立ったじゃない…。
So my experiment turned out
to be somewhat useful...
《実験？》
Experiment...?
木ノ葉には
もう少し感謝してもらいたいわ…。
The Leaf should be thanking me
a little more for this...
ねぇ…。
私のかわいい実験体さん。
Don't you agree...
my adorable little test subject...?
実験体？
この方 いったい何者です？
Test subject?
Who the heck is this person?
昔… 私がまだ
木ノ葉にいた頃の話よ…。
It happened...
a long time ago when I was
still in the Hidden Leaf Village...
すべての忍の中で
唯一 木遁忍術を使い➡
I wanted the power of
the First Hokage,
さらに 尾獣を意のままに
操ることができた➡
the only one among all Shinobi
who could use the Wood Style Ninjutsu
初代火影の力が欲しくてね…。
and control Tailed Beasts at will.
初代の屍から
その中の遺伝子情報を取り出し➡
I once conducted an experiment
where I took some DNA information...
from the remains of the First Hokage
and implanted genetic components...
遺伝的要素を 60体の子供の細胞に
組み込む 人体実験を➡
from that DNA into
the cells of sixty children.
したことがあったんだけど…
拒絶反応が ひどくってね。
But their bodies
violently rejected it,
バタバタ 死んでいったわ。
and they died while
kicking and struggling...
そろそろ 見切りを
つけようと思っていた頃に➡
Around the time when
I was about to give up,
別の実験で 足がついて
木ノ葉を出ることになったの。
I ended up being tracked by
another one of my experiments
and had to leave the village...
実験施設は そのままにしてね。
leaving my laboratory just as it was.
全員 死んだと思ってたけど
まさか 生き残りがいたとはね…。
I thought all the test
subjects had died...
but I never thought one of them
would still be alive.
《そうか…》
I get it...
((四柱牢の術！))
Four-Pillar Prison Jutsu!
《サクラ : こ… これって
初代様だけの秘術…。
Th-This is...the secret Jutsu that only
the First Hokage could use.
木遁忍術！
The Wood Style Ninjutsu!
なんで
ヤマト隊長が木遁忍術を!?》
How come Captain Yamato can use
the Wood Style Ninjutsu?
《だから 初代様だけの木遁を…》
So that's why he can use
the Wood Style
that only the First Hokage
could use...
《そういうことか》
So that's the story...
なるほどね。
I see...
では かつての
研究の成果ともいえる サンプルが➡
So it looks like we'll now
be able to obtain
今ここで 手に入りそうですね。
a sample from a product
of old research.
そんなことより 今は…
私のサスケ君が➡
More important than that...
I'd like to test out how strong
my Sasuke has become...
どれくらい強くなってるか…。
ためしに 目の前のナルト君と
やらせてみたいわね。
by having him
fight against Naruto.
テメエの…。
He doesn't...
テメエのもんじゃねえ…！
ふぅ…！ くっ！
うぅ…！
オレの前で… 自分のものみてぇに➡
サスケの名を口にするんじゃねえ！
くっ…！ あれは！
《なんなの!? あのチャクラ…》
《くっ… 空気が痛い》
グルルルル…！
おもしろい…。
《間違いない。
妖狐の衣… ３本目まで…》
《あ… あれが 人柱力の力…。
肌で感じてわかる…。
これは…
こんな おぞましいチャクラ➡
コントロールできるような質の
チャクラじゃない！》
《これが うずまき ナルト…》
《九尾の力か…》
ぐおぉ～!!
＜ヤマト : 大蛇丸の側近 薬師 カブト。
その実像は 謎に包まれている＞
＜カブトは 桔梗峠の戦いの戦場にて
発見され➡
木ノ葉の医療部隊隊長に
養子として引き取られた。
ゆえに その詳しい出生を
知る者はいない＞
＜木ノ葉では 平凡な下忍を装い
その力を隠し続け➡
実際の戦闘では
医療忍術のセンスとキレで➡
綱手様をも窮地に追い詰めた。
もともと カブトは 暁のサソリが
大蛇丸に差し向けたスパイだった。
ところが 大蛇丸に共感し
自ら寝返ったというが➡
カブト自身の目的は わかっていない。
今後も カブトの動向に注意を払い
調査を重ねる必要があるだろう＞